Guide to the Robert Stanley Breed papers, [ca. 1901-1943]
Breed, Robert Stanley papers, [ca. 1901-1943]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Stanley Breed papers, [ca. 1901-1943]
22-2-662
Robert S. Breed, 1877-1956.
16 cubic ft.
Correspondence, reports, notebooks, programs, questionnaires.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence with other bacteriologists, farmers, and public health officials.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Chief in Research Bacteriology, N.Y.S. Experiment Station at Geneva, and Professor of Bacteriology, 1913-1947.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence with other bacteriologists, farmers, and public health officials including the N.Y.S. Department of Health and the U.S. Public Health Service, the Dairymen's League and the International Milk Dealers, and Cornell administrators; mainly concerns Breed's work in dairy bacteriology with a special emphasis on problems of dairy sanitation, standards of milk production and distribution, methods of milk analysis, and his participation in the work of the American Public Health Association; also, related reports, data, notes, and printed material. Included are notebooks (1909-1911) containing research data and class notes, some relating to Breed's study at the Universities of Gèottingen and Kiel; a record of examination (1911) of the Experiment Station herd; programs, abstracts of addresses, and reports pertaining to world dairy congresses, in which Breed took a prominent part; correspondence and reports concerning Breed's work as Supervisor of Milk and Water in Geneva, N.Y., and membership on the Board of Health there; and completed questionnaires answered by state, municipal, milk dealer, private, and commercial laboratories throughout the United States (1936) as part of a study of milk samples examined by these laboratories in routine milk control, undertaken by the Standard Methods Committee of the American Public Health Association, of which Breed was chairman.
Harold J. Conn, Arthur P. Hitchens, Friend Lee Mickle, and William A. Stocking are among the correspondents.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Breed, Robert S., 1877-1956.; Conn, H. J. (Harold Joel), 1886-1975.; Hitchens, Arthur Parker, 1877-1948.; Mickle, Friend Lee.; Stocking, William Alonzo, 1872-1926.; American Public Health Association.; Dairymen's League.; Geneva (N.Y.). Board of Health.; International Milk Dealers.; New York (State). Dept. of Health.; United States. Public Health Service.; Universitèat Gèottingen.; Universitèat Kiel.
Subjects:
Public health--New York (State)--Geneva.; Public health administration--New York (State)--Geneva.; Dairy bacteriology.; Milk--Sterilization.; Milk hygiene.; Milk--Microbiology.; Milk yield.; Bacteriologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- 1925-1928
  - Misc. loose in front of box - various state health depts. correspondence, etc. (Box 1)
  - 1 Austin, G.P. (Borden's) (Box 1)
  - 2 Bausch and Lomb Optical Co., Rochester, N.Y. (Box 1)
  - Dr. Paul Brooks (Box 1)
  - 1 Amer. Dairy Science Association, Comm. on Bact. Methods (Box 1)
  - 1 American Public Health Association, H.N. Claver, Secy. (Box 1)
  - 1 Applications (Box 1)
  - A 1 (Box 1)
  - Bi-Bri 3 (to Brn) (Box 1)
  - Ca-Cl 5 (to Cn) (Box 1)
  - Co-Cy 6 (to Cz) (Box 1)
  - E 8 (Box 1)
  - D 7 (Box 1)
  - 6 Cornell University Graduate School - Kenniston (Box 1)
  - F 9 (Box 1)
  - Ga-Gl 10 (to Gn) (Box 1)
  - Go-Gy 11 (to Gz) (Box 1)
  - 10 Geneva Board of Health, Reports on Milk Supply (Box 1)
  - 10 Geneva Board of Health, Accredited Herd Testing (Box 1)
  - Geneva Board of Health, Annual Report (Box 1)
  - Ha 12 (Box 1)
  - He-Hi 13 (to Hn) (Box 1)
  - Ho-Hy 14 (to Hz) (Box 1)
  - J 16 (Box 1)
  - 16 Jordan, Dr. E.O. (Box 1)
  - 19 B.E. Livingston (Box 1)
  - K 17 (Box 1)
- 1925-1928
  - 18 N.E. Lazarus (Box 2)
  - 19 Little, R.S., International Milk Dealers (Box 2)
  - Li-Ly 19 (to Lz) (Box 2)
  - La-Le 18 (to Lh) (Box 2)
  - Livingstone, B.E., A.A.A.S. Grant (Box 2)
  - Lehmann and Newmann (Box 2)
  - 20 W.L. Marcussen - Bordens' Farm Products Company (Box 2)
  - A.R. Mann (Box 2)
  - Ma-Mc 20 (to Md) (Box 2)
  - Sa (to Sb) (Box 2)
  - Ruehle (Box 2)
  - Me-Mi 21 (to Mn) (Box 2)
  - 21 Mr. F.L. Mickle (Box 2)
  - 22 Mudge, C.S. (Box 2)
  - Mo-My 22 (to Mz) (Box 2)
  - N 23 (Box 2)
  - 23 Norton, Dr. J.F. (Box 2)
  - 23 N.Y. State Dept. Health - General (Box 2)
  - 23 N.Y. State Dept. Health - Lab., Wadsworth, Watcher, Gilbert (Box 2)
  - 23 N.Y. Dept. Farms and Markets, B.A. Pyrke, K.F. Fee, etc. (Box 2)
  - 23 N.Y.A.E.S. - News Letters (Box 2)
  - O 24 (Box 2)
  - Pa-Pe 25 (to Ph) (Box 2)
  - Pi-Py 26 (to Pz) (Box 2)
  - Powers, A.J. (Box 2)
  - 26 Prickett, Paul S. (Box 2)
  - 26 Pipette Standardization (Box 2)
  - Q 27 (Box 2)
  - 28 Rankin, A.J. (Box 2)
  - 28 L.F. Rettger (Box 2)
  - Ra-Ri 28 (to Rn) (Box 2)
  - 32 Stechert, G.E. and Co. (Box 2)
  - Ro-Ry 29 (to Rz) (Box 2)
  - Sti-Sy 33 (to Sz) (Box 2)
  - T 34 (Box 2)
  - #2 Standard Methods Committee, Milk Report, 5th Edition (Box 2)
  - V (Box 2)
  - V 147 (Box 3)
- 1932-1936
  - 19 Little, Mr. R.E. (Box 3)
  - Lab Control Bill (Box 3)
  - L (Box 3)
  - 20 Market Milk Report Manuscripts (Box 3)
  - Milk - Grade A, Plamt Work (Box 3)
  - 20 Macy, Dr. Harold (Box 3)
  - M (Box 3)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L. (Box 3)
  - N (Box 3)
  - 23 Norton, J.F. (Box 3)
  - 19 Library (Box 3)
  - 22 Murray, Prof. E.G.D., McGill Univ., Montreal, Can. (Box 3)
  - 29 Robertson, A.H. (Box 3)
  - O (Box 3)
  - Ohio Matter (Box 3)
  - Rome Dairy, Congress, Other (Box 3)
  - P (Box 3)
  - Powers, A.J. and others on Milk Sampling (Box 3)
  - 26 Prickett, P.S. (Box 3)
  - 26 Powers, Dr. A.J. (Box 3)
  - 31 Sherman, J.M. (Box 3)
  - S (Box 3)
  - T (Box 3)
  - Telegram and Long Distance Telephone Record (Box 3)
  - 34 Travel Fund - Copies of Expense Accounts, 1934-1935 (Box 3)
  - 34 Thorton, H.R. (Box 3)
  - 34 Tiedeman, W.D., Bureau Milk Sanitation (Box 3)
  - V (Box 3)
  - 38 Williams and Wilkins Co. (Box 3)
  - 38 Winslow, Dr. C.E.A., Yale University, New Haven (Box 3)
  - W (Box 3)
  - XYZ (Box 3)
  - A, 1936 (Box 3)
  - B, 1936 (Box 3)
  - B - Special Files, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Breed (Box 3)
  - C, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 6 Covert, Elfreda, National Youth Administration (Box 3)
  - D, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Dairy Day, 1935 (Box 3)
  - E, 1936 (Box 3)
  - F, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 10 Geneva Board of Health, Geneva, New York (Box 3)
  - F - Special File, 1936 (Box 3)
  - G, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 10 General Dairy Products Committee (Box 3)
  - 10 Gilbert, Ruth, Licenses, etc. (Box 3)
  - H - Special Folders, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 13 Hedrick, Dr. Paul G. (Box 3)
  - H, 1936 (Box 3)
  - I, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 15 Ice Cream - Bacteriological Methods of Examining (Box 3)
  - 15 Irwin, Ralph E. (Box 3)
  - J, 1936 (Box 3)
  - K, 1936 (Box 3)
  - L, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 19 Library (Box 3)
  - 19 Little, Mr. R.E., 228 North La Salle, Chicago (Box 3)
  - London Congress (Box 3)
  - M, 1936 (Box 3)
  - 20 Market Milk Report Letters (Box 3)
- 1932-1936
  - Mr. Mickle - Alleghany Matter (Box 4)
  - 21 Microbiological Congress, London, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 21 Milk Control Board (Box 4)
  - M - Special Files, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 22 Morris, F.B. (Box 4)
  - N, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 23 New York State Fair Contest (Box 4)
  - 23 Norton, Dr. J.F., Detroit, Michigan (Box 4)
  - O, 1936 (Box 4)
  - PQ, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 25 Special P File, 1936 (Box 4)
  - R, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 29 Robertson, Dr. H.A., Director, State Food Lab. (Box 4)
  - R - Special File, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 30 S - Special File, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 31 Simons, L.R., Director of Extension (Box 4)
  - Sour Milk Correspondence, "Keifer," etc. (Box 4)
  - T, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 34 Tiedeman, W.D. (Box 4)
  - U, 1936 (Box 4)
  - V, 1936 (Box 4)
  - S, 1936 (Box 4)
  - W - Special File, 1936 (Box 4)
  - XYZ, 1936 (Box 4)
  - 17 Sub-proj. C 1, Bacterial and plant studies of mineral salts stimulating growth in certain soils - Coop. with Hort. (Orchard soils _____, Project No. 13) (Box 4)
  - New Questionnaires (Box 4)
  - Questionnaire Letters (Box 4)
  - Alabama (Box 4)
  - Arkansas (Box 4)
  - Arizona (Box 4)
  - California (Box 4)
  - Canada (Box 4)
  - Colorado (Box 4)
  - Connecticut (Box 4)
  - Washinton, D.C. (Box 4)
  - Delaware (Box 4)
  - Florida (Box 4)
  - Georgia (Box 4)
  - Illinois (Box 4)
  - Idaho (Box 4)
  - Indiana (Box 4)
  - Iowa (Box 4)
  - Kansas (Box 4)
  - Kentucky (Box 4)
  - Louisiana (Box 4)
  - Massachusettes (Box 4)
  - Maine (Box 4)
  - Maryland (Box 4)
  - Michigan (Box 4)
  - Minnesota (Box 4)
  - Missouri (Box 4)
  - Ice Cream (Box 4)
  - Commercial (Box 4)
  - Nebraska (Box 4)
  - New Jersey (Box 4)
  - New York (Box 4)
  - North Carolina (Box 4)
  - North and South Dakota (Box 4)
  - Ohio (Box 4)
  - Oklahoma (Box 4)
  - Oregon (Box 4)
- A-L, 1936-1939
  - B (Box 5)
  - A (Box 5)
  - A, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Air Analysis (Box 5)
  - 1 Associated Council of Agricultural Societies (Box 5)
  - 1 Advisory Committee on Milk Sanitation (Letters) (Box 5)
  - 1 American Type Culture Collection - 637S Wood, Chicago (Box 5)
  - Berlin Congress, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Bankhead-Jones Position (Box 5)
  - B, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Cooling Equipment (Box 5)
  - C (Box 5)
  - C, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Current Dairy Information (Box 5)
  - 6 Cornell University Graduate School, and other material (Box 5)
  - D (Box 5)
  - D, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Dunham, H.G., The Difco Co. (Box 5)
  - E (Box 5)
  - E, 1938 (Box 5)
  - F (Box 5)
  - F, 1938 (Box 5)
  - G (Box 5)
  - G, 1938 (Box 5)
  - 10 Gilcreas - Dept. of Health (Box 5)
  - Goat Letters (Box 5)
  - Grade A Milk Plants (Box 5)
  - H, 1938 (Box 5)
  - I (Box 5)
  - I, 1938 (Box 5)
  - 15 International Committee (Rotary) (Box 5)
  - J (Box 5)
  - J, 1938 (Box 5)
  - K (Box 5)
  - K, 1938 (Box 5)
  - L (Box 5)
  - L, 1938 (Box 5)
- L-Z, 1936-1939
  - Laundry File (Box 6)
  - Mr. Luckett - Reprint Orders (Box 6)
  - M (Box 6)
  - 20 Mastitis Indemnity Bill (Box 6)
  - Milk Report Proof (Box 6)
  - M, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Grading by Microscopic Technic (Box 6)
  - 20 Market Milk Comm. of Amer, Dairy Sci., Assoc. (Box 6)
  - N (Box 6)
  - N, 1938 (Box 6)
  - O (Box 6)
  - Office Equipment Quotations (Box 6)
  - P (Box 6)
  - P, 1938 (Box 6)
  - R (Box 6)
  - Q (Box 6)
  - R, 1938 (Box 6)
  - S (Box 6)
  - 29 Robinson, Dr. Montgomery, Ithaca (Box 6)
  - Rotary (Box 6)
  - 29 Rotary Club (Box 6)
  - S, 1938 (Box 6)
  - T, 1938 (Box 6)
  - T (Box 6)
  - 30 Sampling Grade A. Plants (Box 6)
  - 34 Tiedeman, W.D. (Box 6)
  - 34 Thompson, Luther, Actinobacillus - N.P. Sherwood, W.A. Hagan, R.E. Buchanan, Dr. Pacheco (Box 6)
  - U (Box 6)
  - Utica Meeting (Box 6)
  - V (Box 6)
  - V, 1938 (Box 6)
  - W (Box 6)
  - W, 1938 (Box 6)
  - 38 Wills, Dr. J.G. (Box 6)
  - XYZ (Box 6)
  - XYZ, 1938 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence, including foreign, c. 1922-1925 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 7)
  - 1935 Annual Report (in French) of the Laboratoire Intercommunal (Box 7)
  - 1936 Annual Report (in French) of the Laboratoire Intercommunal (Box 7)
  - Descriptive Catalogue, No. 1, Naturalist's Supplies, Richard Kny and Co., Department of Natural Science, New York, Berlin (Box 7)
  - Report of the Director of the College of Ag., CU for 1901-1902, Prof. I.P. Roberts, Ithaca, N.Y. (Box 7)
  - Program of American Meeting in honor of Pasteur at the Sorbonne, May 22, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Program (?) in French, Exposition Scientifique et Industrielle d'Hygiene, Stasbourg, June 1923-Oct. 1923 (Box 7)
  - Maine Sportsman, Big Game Review Number, Jan. 1901 (Box 7)
  - The Sanitary Inspector, Vol. XIV, No. 1, Mar. 1901 (Box 7)
  - Institut Pasteur, 1922 (Box 7)
  - L'Hygiene du Lait, pamphlet, second edition, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Menu, (French), occasion having to do with Pasteur (Box 7)
  - Program in French, Fetes du Centenaire de Pasteur (Box 7)
  - N.Y.S. Assoc. of Public Health Labs, Programs; June 2, 1930, Nov. 23, 1928, Nov. 1, 1922, June 3, 1929, June 2, 1939, Nov. 7, 1930, Nov. 4, 1925, Mar. 30, 1926, Nov. 12, 1926, 1923, Nov. 4, 1927 (2), 1926 (Box 7)
  - New York State Association of Food Control Officers, Application Blank (and corres.) (Box 7)
  - Notebook: Number of cells in Milk, Record of examinations of Exper. Sta. Herd and White Springs Farm Dairy Herd by R.S. Breed, 1911- (Box 7)
  - Notebook: Historical Studies, Record of Work done at Kiel under Prof. Fr. Meres, by R.S. Breed, 1911 (Box 7)
  - Five notebooks, thin (Box 7)
  - Sheets of tabulations (Box 7)
  - Cooperative effort in Eradicating Bovine Tuberculosis, R.S. Breed, Geneva City Lab (carbon transcript) (Box 7)
  - Other misc. corres. and printed material (Box 7)
  - Abstract of Title to Real Estate from Registry of Deeds (Box 7)
  - Pasteur Program (in French) (Box 7)
  - Pasteur, Hotel de Ville de Paris, May 26, 1923 (program) (Box 7)
  - Notebook: Observations on number cells, precip. of cells by centrif..., Breed, 1910, Germany (Box 7)
- A-L, 1939-1943, milk and food technology
  - A-AP, HA (Box 8)
  - Atlantic City Meeting, Oct. 13-17, 1941 (Box 8)
  - 1 Atwater, Dr. R.M. (Box 8)
  - A Paper Cont. (Box 8)
  - Abele and others regarding Cooperative tests (Box 8)
  - B - Paper (Box 8)
  - B - AP (Box 8)
  - C - AP (Box 8)
  - Detroit Meeting, APHA, 1940 (Box 8)
  - D - AP (Box 8)
  - D - Paper (Box 8)
  - E - AP (Box 8)
  - E - Paper (Box 8)
  - F - Paper (Box 8)
  - 9 Frozen Desserts Committee (Box 8)
  - F - AP (Box 8)
  - G - AP (Box 8)
  - G - Paper (Box 8)
  - 13 Hitchend, Dr. A.P. (Box 8)
  - H - AP (Box 8)
  - H - Paper (Box 8)
  - June Meeting (Box 8)
  - I-J - Paper (Box 8)
  - Kline - E.K. (Box 8)
  - K - AP (Box 8)
  - Kansas City Meeting (Box 8)
  - K - Paper (Box 8)
  - 18 Landy, Miss Isabel, 50 West 50th Street, New York (Box 8)
  - L - APHA (Box 8)
  - Lincoln. Geo. J. (Box 8)
  - L - Paper (Box 8)
- M-Z, 1939-1943, milk and food technology
  - I - McCrady, M.H. (Box 9)
  - M - Paper (Box 9)
  - M - APHA (Box 9)
  - Mickle, Dr. F.L. (Box 9)
  - Mott, Frank E., Room 1104, City Hall Annex, Boston, Mass., City Inspector and Chemist (Box 9)
  - N - APHA (Box 9)
  - N - Paper (Box 9)
  - O (Box 9)
  - Phosphotase Test (Box 9)
  - Phosphotase Test (Box 9)
  - P - APHA (Box 9)
  - Perry, C.A. - Shellfish Work, May 1938 (Box 9)
  - Program Pittsburg (Box 9)
  - American Public Health Assoc. Program, St. Louis, Oct. 1942 (Box 9)
  - Peptone File, Nov. 1, 1938 (Box 9)
  - P and Q - Paper (Box 9)
  - 29 Dr. A.H. Robertson, Director State Food Laboratory, Albany, New York (Box 9)
  - Q - APHA, 1938 (Box 9)
  - R - APHA (Box 9)
  - Sections A and R (Robertson) (Box 9)
  - W - APHA (Box 9)
  - Streptococcus Conference (Box 9)
  - Streptococcus Questionnaires (Box 9)
  - S - Paper (Box 9)
  - S - APHA (Box 9)
  - T - APHA (Box 9)
  - TUV - Paper (Box 9)
  - WXYZ (Box 9)
  - Wheaton, Evan (Box 9)
- Geneva Experimental Station
  - Volume: Collected Studies from the Department of Pathology and Bacteriology, University of Illinois, College of Medicine, Chicago, Vol. VII, 1924-1925 (Box 10)
  - 5 letterboxes (?) filled with miscellany, labeled: (Box 10)
    International Dairy Congress, Rome, 1934
    World's Dairy Congress, Rome, 1934
    World's Dairy Congress, Abstracts and Programs, Washington, Philadelphia, Syracuse, 1923
    International Dairy Congress (Fifth) Stokkholm, 1911
    International Dairy Congress, United States, 1923
  - 4 letterboxes (?) containing miscellany and printed material: (Box 11)
    World's Dairy Congress, Great Britain, 1928; Copenhagen, 1931
    International Dairy Congress, Rome, 1934; Berlin, 1937
    International Dairy Congress (Sixth), Bern, 1914
    World's Dairy Congress, 1928
  - Cardboard thing (?) containing printed matter on leucocytes (Box 12)
  - Same, labeled American Public Health Assoc. Programs (Box 12)
  - Same, labeled International Dairy Congress, Secretary General's Report; 1907, 1910-1913, 1922 (Box 12)
  - Same, labeled International Botanical Congress, Cambridge, 1930. International Congress of Comparative Pathology, (ninth) Rome, 1939 (Box 12)
  - 5 unlabeled folders containg printed material (Box 12)
- Geneva Experimental Station correspondence
  - C.P. Merlino (Box 13)
  - Mes-Mez (to Mh) (Box 13)
  - Mia-Mil (Box 13)
  - Mia-Mil 98 (Box 13)
  - Mickle, F.L. (Box 13)
  - Mim-Miz (to Mn) (Box 13)
  - Mo (to Mt) (Box 13)
  - Mu-My (to Mz) (Box 13)
  - N 104 (Box 13)
  - 23 National Research Council, 1923-1924, J.R. Schramm (Box 13)
  - 23 National Research Council, J.R. Schramm-Lille, Jones, Howard Count (Box 13)
  - 23 National Research Council, C.E. McClung, Howard Court (Box 13)
  - 23 National Seal Company (Box 13)
  - 22 V.A. Moore (Box 13)
  - Na-Nd (Box 13)
  - Na 102 (to Nd) (Box 13)
  - Ne-Nh (Box 13)
  - Ni-No (to Nt) (Box 13)
  - Same, 104 (Box 13)
  - Ne 103 (to Nh), N.Y. Dept. Farms and Markets (Box 13)
  - Nu-Way (Box 13)
  - O 107 (Box 13)
  - O'A-O'Z 106 (Box 13)
  - Oa-Oz (Box 13)
  - P 108 (to Pd) (Box 13)
  - Pa (to Pd) (Box 13)
  - 25 Pasteur Institute (Box 13)
  - 25 W.H. Park (Box 13)
  - Pe (Box 13)
  - Perfection (Box 13)
  - 25 Phelps, E.B. (Box 13)
  - Pi (to Pk) (Box 13)
  - P 112 Pinr Tree Milking Machine Co. (Box 13)
  - Pine Tree (Box 13)
  - Po (to Pq) (Box 13)
  - 26 C.H. Porcher, Le Lait (Box 13)
  - 26 Powers Accounting Machine Co. (Box 13)
  - Pr-Ps. (to Pt) (Box 13)
  - Q 114 (Box 13)
  - Q (Box 13)
  - R (Box 13)
  - Ra (to Rd) (Box 13)
  - Re-Rh (Box 13)
  - Ri (to Rn) (Box 13)
  - Roa-Rof (Box 13)
  - Robertson, A.H. (Box 13)
  - Rog-Ros (Box 13)
  - Rot-Roy (to Rt) (Box 13)
  - Ru-Ry (to Rz) (Box 13)
  - Ole Salthe (Box 14)
  - 32 Standard Methods Committee, R.G. Perkins (Box 14)
  - Stevens and H.J.C. (Box 14)
  - 32 Standard Methods Committee, E.C.L. Miller (Box 14)
  - Shi-Shy (to Shz) (Box 14)
  - Si-Sme (to Smh) (Box 14)
  - Sharpless (Box 14)
  - Smith (Box 14)
  - Sha-She (to Shh) (Box 14)
  - S 124 (Box 14)
  - Sti-Sty (to Stz) (Box 14)
  - Sci-Scy (to Sd) (Box 14)
  - Scho-Schy (to Schz) (Box 14)
  - 31 Sediment Testers (Box 14)
  - Scha-Schl (to Schn) (Box 14)
  - Sn-So (Box 14)
  - Sp-Sq (to Ss) (Box 14)
  - Ste (to Sth) (Box 14)
  - Su-Sy (to Sz) (Box 14)
  - 32 Standard Methods Committee, J.F. Norton, Secy. (Box 14)
  - W.A. Stocking, 1914-1918 (Box 14)
  - T 141 (Box 14)
  - 33 W.A. Stocking (Box 14)
  - Ta-Te (to Tg) (Box 14)
  - Th (Box 14)
  - 34 Taylor, Geo. B. (Box 14)
  - To (to Tq) (Box 14)
  - Tr-Tu-Ty (to Tz) (Box 14)
  - U (Box 14)
  - U 146 (Box 14)
  - Universal (Box 14)
  - 23 Whey Pasteurization (Box 14)
  - Will Corp. (Box 14)
  - Waa-Wal (Box 14)
  - Wil (Box 14)
  - Wia-Wik (Box 14)
  - Wh (Box 14)
  - Wel-Wey (to Wp) (Box 14)
  - Wam-Way (to Wd) (Box 14)
  - Wea-Wek (Box 14)
  - Williams and Wilkins (Box 14)
  - W 148 (Box 14)
  - Williams, Linsley R. (Box 14)
  - C.E.A. Winslow (Box 14)
  - Wim-Wiz (to Wn) (Box 14)
  - Wo-Wr (to Wt) (Box 14)
  - World's Dairy Congress (Box 14)
  - Y (inc. X) (Box 14)
  - 3 Breed Family Assoc. (Box 15)
  - E (Box 15)
  - 9 Fred, Dr. E.B. (Box 15)
  - 7 Downs, Dr. P.A., Univ. of Nebraska (Box 15)
  - 7 Dry Milk (Box 15)
  - G (Box 15)
  - 11 Grove, Dr. C.W., Health Officer (Box 15)
  - F (Box 15)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 15)
  - APHA Water nd Sewage Commission, Norton, J.F., Chairman, Kalamazoo (Box 15)
  - Extra copies, Milwaukee Manuscripts (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Coordinating Committee, APHA (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Food Handler's Committee of APHA (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Dairy and Food Products Committee (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Food and Nutrition Section, APHA (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Governing Council, APHA (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Regarding Laboratory Section (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Milwaukee Program, Minutes, Correspondence on Papers, etc. (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Shellfish Committee Matters (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., Standard Methods Comm., APHA (Box 15)
  - 20 Mickle, F.L., Montreal, Can., Dairy and Food Products Committee (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., General APHA Correspondence (Box 15)
  - Parker, Dr. H.N. (Box 15)
  - Parker, M.E., Ch. Res. Com. Am. Assoc., Cry. Butter Mfgrs. (Box 15)
  - New Orleans Program, July, August, September (Box 15)
  - 31 Shellfish Report, 1935-1936 (Box 15)
    Folder contains other folders: 1. 25 Perry, Dr. C.A.; 2. 28 Revenel, Dr. M.P.; 3. 28 Reynolds, F.H.K.; 4. Siemer, Elsie
  - Standard Methods (Vitamin D), Scott (Box 15)
  - 33 Stovall, W.D., Madison, Wisconsin, Diagnostic Procedures and Reagents (Box 15)
  - 34 Thorton, H.R., Edmonton, Alta, Canada (Box 15)
  - Thompson, A.T., Army Medical School (Box 15)
  - 37 Walsh, Mrs. Willimina Rayne, 50 West 50th Street, N.Y.C. (Box 15)
  - 1 American Public Health Assoc., General Correspondence to 1935 (Box 15)
  - 3 APHA Dairy and Food Prod. Comm., Blanck, Dr. F.C., Washington (Box 15)
  - APHA Carson, Caryl C., Milk Sediment Standards (Box 15)
  - APHA Committee on Dairy and Food Products (Box 15)
  - 8 Emerson, Dr. Kendall, Amer. Pub. Health Assoc. (Box 15)
  - 8 Eddy, Dr. Walter, New York (Box 15)
  - 9 Fellers, Dr. C.R. (Box 15)
  - 16 Mrs. Jay, American Public Health (Box 15)
  - 16 APHA Comm. on Food and Nutrition; James, Dr. L.H. Chairman, Washington (Box 15)
  - 17 Kellogg, Dr. W.H., Dir. State Sept. Health Lab., Berkeley, CA (Box 15)
  - 17 Kline, E.K., APHA (Box 15)
  - 18 Landy, Miss Isabel, APHA (Box 15)
  - 1 APHA, Laboratory Section (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L., APHA, Joint Program, Food and Nutrition (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle on Governing Council (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Food and Nutrition Section (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Dairy and Food Products (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Coordinating Committee (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Committee on Standard Methods (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding bact. exam of food handlers (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Laboratory Section (Box 15)
  - Milwaukee file of minutes of meeting and abstracts of papers (Box 15)
  - 32 Reorganization Committee on Standard Methods (Box 15)
  - 21 Milwaukee Program (General Correspondence) (Box 15)
  - 21 Milwaukee Program (Mr. Mickle) (Box 15)
  - 21 Mr. F.L. Mickle, General Correspondence (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Water and Sewage Committee (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Swimming Pool and Bathing Place Waters (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Standardization of Biological Products (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Shellfish Committee (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Journals Matters (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Meeting and Publications Comm. (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Research and Standards Comm. (Box 15)
  - Mr. Mickle, re Milk Report (Box 15)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L. for Amer. Pub. Health Assoc. (Box 16)
  - Mr. Mickle regarding Laboratory Section (Box 16)
  - 21 Mickle, F.L. for Amer. Pub. Health Assoc. (Box 16)
  - 21 APHA Program, Milwaukee meeting (Box 16)
  - 20 APHA Dairy and Food Prod. Comm., McCrady, M.H., Montreal (Box 16)
  - 6 APHA Comm. on Standardization, Dr. W.H. Park, Chairman (Box 16)
  - 25 Perry, Dr. C.A., and others regarding shellfish work, 1935 (Box 16)
  - 25 Perry, Dr. C.A., shellfish, 1934 (Box 16)
  - Minutes of Pasadena meeting (Box 16)
  - Pasadena meeting APHA (Box 16)
  - Standard Methods, 1932-1933 (Box 16)
  - APHA Dairy and Food Prod. Comm., Robertson, A.H., Albany (Box 16)
  - Ravenel, Dr. M.P. (Box 16)
  - Stovall, W.D. (Box 16)
  - Stone, Dr. R.V., Pasadena, CA (Box 16)
  - 32 Standard Methods, Oyster, Shellfish (Tarbett) (Box 16)
  - APHA Comm. on Res. and Standards, Wolman, Dr. Abel, Chairman (Box 16)
  - 37 APHA Comm. on Standardization, Wadsworth, A.W., Albany, New York (Box 16)
  - 37 Walsh, Mrs. W.R., Amer. Public Health Assoc. (Box 16)
  - Standard Methods, Foreign Correspondence, England, Germany (Box 16)
  - Standard Methods, Color Test (Box 16)
  - Bacteriological Methods, Sixth edition (Box 16)
  - Butter and Cream (Box 16)
  - Chemical Methods, Sixth edition (Box 16)